<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Free | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/free/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T22:07:43+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[blog@fragmentedmemory.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Free Mac Applications]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/30/useful-free-mac-applications/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-30T20:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/30/useful-free-mac-applications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I'm tight, if there is a free tool to do something I will find it.  It is a bit harder work to find those applications when you use a Mac, but I have over my time using my Macbook Pro found plenty of stuff to help me get full use out of my computer.  So I thought I would share them:<br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.adiumx.com/">Adium</a> - Instant messaging with the GAIM base.</li><li><a href="http://metaquark.de/appfresh/">AppFresh</a> - Make sure that installed programs are up to date.</li><li><a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a> - Edit audio files (I used it to make iPhone ringtones).</li><li><a href="http://www.bean-osx.com/">Bean</a> - Simple and easy to use document editing.</li><li><a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/chamonix/">Chamonix</a> - A CHM reader for OSX.</li><li><a href="http://projects.digitalwaters.net/index.php?q=cocopad">Cocopad</a> - A simple scribbler application.</li><li><a href="http://cord.sourceforge.net/">CoRD</a> - Connect to other computers using the MS remote desktop protocol.</li><li><a href="http://www.blocksoft.net/docker.html">Docker</a> - Lots of settings for the dock on Leopard.</li><li><a href="http://eclipse.org">Eclipse</a> - The ubiquitous platform for IDEs.</li><li><a href="http://getfirefox.com">Firefox</a> - Because I love the plug-ins.  I'll doa post about them another time to geta more integrated Firefox (could be moot with v3.0).</li><li><a href="http://earth.google.com/">Google Earth</a> - Because i wanted to see old maps wrapped around the globe.</li><li><a href="http://toolbar.google.com/gmail-helper/notifier_mac.html">Google Notifier</a> - Keep an eye on your Google inbox.</li><li><a href="http://gridwars.marune.de/">Gridwars</a> - Free game allegedly like Geometry Wars.</li><li><a href="http://handbrake.fr/">Handbrake</a> - Rip movies to your desired format.</li><li><a href="http://www.inkscape.org/">Inkscape</a> - Vector drawing.</li><li><a href="http://www.macports.org/">MacPorts</a> - Package manager for thousands of open-source programs.  I have mentioned <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/07/great-free-software-macports.html">this before</a>.<br /></li><li><a href="http://www.mactheripper.org/">MacTheRipper</a> - DVD ripping.</li><li><a href="http://sbooth.org/Max/">Max</a> - CD ripping software.</li><li><a href="http://www.neooffice.org">NeoOffice</a> - OpenOffice integrated Aqua style.</li><li><a href="http://www.titanium.free.fr/pgs2/english/download.html">Onyx</a> - More settings for your Mac!</li><li><a href="http://perian.org/">Perian</a> - Loads of codecs for OSX.<br /></li><li><a href="http://opensword.org/Pixen/">Pixen</a> - Simple art package.</li><li><a href="http://porticus.alittledrop.com/">Porticus</a> - Great Cocoa front-end for MacPorts.</li><li><a href="http://www.fadingred.org/senuti/">Senuti</a> - Get music from your iPod back to your computer.</li><li><a href="http://www.lachoseinteractive.net/en/community/subversion/svnx/features/">SvnX</a> - Graphical front-end for Subversion.</li><li><a href="http://scplugin.tigris.org/">scplugin</a> - TortoiseSVN style integration for the Mac.</li><li><a href="http://www.bresink.de/osx/TinkerTool.html">TinkerTool</a> - More settings for the Mac.</li><li><a href="http://www.videolan.org/vlc/">VLC</a> - Great open-source video player.</li></ul>I tend to prefer open-source to free in most instances, and MacPorts (with Porticus) gives so much that it deserves more than a one line description...  oh well ;)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Anti-Virus]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/11/free-anti-virus/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-11T09:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/11/free-anti-virus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<span style="font-weight:bold;">UPDATED</span><br /><br />Damn, I wake up this morning and switch on the computer to discover that AVG are discontinuing the <a href="http://free.grisoft.com/">free edition of their anti-virus suite</a> as of January 2007.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">START UPDATE</span><br />Well, the message as it turns out was a bit misleading.  They are discontinuing 7.1 free edition and are advising the users to update to 7.5 which is still free.  Click the link in the first paragraph to download - incidentally it uses <a href="http://www.wxwidgets.org">wxWidgets</a> for its user interface.<br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">END UPDATE</span><br /><br />It has been a fairly decent product, especially for the price, and has meant that I don't have to install one of the myriad of Norton Security packages that I own (normally given away free with computer parts).  I suppose I could go and install those, but I am not really pleased with the software when I have used it.  Mainly due to <a href="http://www.getfirefox.com/">Firefox</a> AVG Free Edition has only spotted one virus attempting to get on my PC in the past few years - and this is definitely not from being a poor anti-virus.<br /><br />Anyway here is a list of free alternatives for all of you in the same position:<br /><ul><li>It seems <a href="http://www.avast.com/eng/avast_4_home.html">Avast</a> is the most fully featured and professional program you could choose.</li><li><a href="http://www.free-av.com/">Avira AntiVir</a> is also a well respected free anti-virus alternative.</li><li>And now an open-source alternative:</li><li><a href="http://www.clamwin.com/">Clamwin</a> - A free open-source anti-virus engine. It is a static scanner... but pair it up with...</li><li><a href="http://winpooch.free.fr/">WinPooch</a> is a dynamic monitoring engine that you can use with ClamWin which gives you all the benefits of dynamic monitoring.</li></ul><br />Well, that is at least a list to be getting on with.  Or you could believe <a href="http://www.betanews.com/article/Allchin_Suggests_Vista_Wont_Need_Antivirus/1163104965">Microsoft's Jim Allchin that you do not need Anti-virus in Windows Vista</a>...</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>untouched</div>
<div class='content'>
hi, came across your blog while Googling. i don't think they're discontinuing the free antivirus <em>per se</em>, just the 7.1 version of the free antivirus. users are advised to upgrade to 7.5, that's all.<br />as you said, i've had some experience with AVG and i think it's really good. it traps quite a number of the bugs that circulate, including a number that infect via autorun, which is a rather large issue where i am at the moment.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Burning a DVD ISO on Windows XP]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/10/05/burning-dvd-iso-on-windows-xp/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-05T11:39:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/10/05/burning-dvd-iso-on-windows-xp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I started by downloading the Windows SDK, which had a file extension <span style="font-style:italic;">.img</span>.  After a bit of <a href="http://www.google.com">Googling</a> I found out you can just change the extension to <span style="font-style:italic;">.iso</span>.<br /><br />Now it was time to burn it.  I found out that the ISO Burning Powertoy doesn't work for DVDs.  The software with the DVD drive was so hatefully bad that it was unusable.<br /><br />So I searched out the burning engine from DVDDecrypter which has been split off by the developer after all the raids and legal ranglings.  Now it is called <a href="http://www.imgburn.com/">ImgBurn</a> and it was a case of choosing the ISO then hitting the big button to burn.  Oh, did I mention it was freeware as well?  Top notch stuff.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
