<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vista | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/vista/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T21:16:04+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vista Graphics Hackety Hack]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/02/07/vista-graphics-hackety-hack/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-07T20:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/02/07/vista-graphics-hackety-hack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
There is nothing more depressing than knowing you have to use a computer loaded up with Vista, especially when developing, because it is a constant battle.<br /><br />But deep in the bowels of the OS there are some interesting things, but they tend to be undocumented.  I'm not a fan of the layering of the GUI, and I always wondered if it was possible to use the base parts of the GUI DLLs which things like WP use as teir basis.<br /><br />Some exceedingly talented and clever developers have spent their brain cycles reverse engineering the completely undocumented dwm and milcore.dll (apart from the thumbnail API).  I'm not a fan of all the managed stuff especially since it mainly resoves down to the unmanaged core DLLs anyway.  Go <a href="http://siwu.info/">check out the blog here</a> with lots of videos of some exceedingly clever things.<br /><br />What is even better is that the developer has released it as <a href="http://code.google.com/p/dwmaxx/">open-source</a>.  Hopefully this will provide a basis for more adventurous and useful developments.  With this amount of flexibility available then it should be possible to create something where Vista gets some good productivity gains.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>jd</div>
<div class='content'>
Have you seen the equivalent tricks in Linux with compositing window managers like compiz-fusion?<BR/><BR/>Check out this video http://remixtechnology.com/view/bfg-c2d-video-screenshot<BR/><BR/>Now all I need is a graphics card made in the last 5 years.<BR/><BR/>JD</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GUI Toolkits - MFC v9 - Visual Studio 2008 - An Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/08/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-08T16:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/08/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I blogged a while back about the secret MFC features for VS2008 (MFC v9) <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/10/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008.html">here</a>.  The information was going to appear at Microsoft Technet Europe 2007in a talk by Ale Contenti.<br /><br />Well, I think the talk must have now happened as there are a few posts out here on the Internet about it.<br /><br />You can read one <a href="http://blog.kalmbach-software.de/2007/11/07/mfcupdate-mfc-now-has-a-visual-manager-and-will-add-office-2007-ribbon-controls-and-many-more-features/">here</a> and another <a href="http://www.google.com/translate?u=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.m-ri.de%2Findex.php%2F2007%2F11%2F07%2Fmfc-updates-for-visual-studio-2008-and-beyond-mfcnext%2F&langpair=de|en&hl=en&ie=UTF8">translated here</a>.<br /><br />It amounts to lots of good stuff for native C++ developers on Windows:<br />* Docking windows<br />* Tabbed MDI<br />* Office 2007 theme<br />* Ribbon interface (no visual designer yet though)<br />* Lots of new controls<br />* Skins<br />* Vista specific enhancements<br />* And plenty more...<br /><br />I actually can't wait to get my hands on this and have a play, unfortunately we do have to wait until next month for a release candidate as it will be an add-on.  The interesting thing is the visual styles manager which will allow switching visual styles at runtime.<br /><br />Apparently there will be a Channel 9 video soon that should appear <a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Showforum.aspx?forumid=14&tagid=17">here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL on Vista]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/04/24/opengl-on-vista/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-24T22:09:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/04/24/opengl-on-vista</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Even though Windows Vista has been out a few months the myth that OpenGL is being degraded is still being perpetuated.  Even though it was debunked what seems like at least a year ago the story just seems to have legs.<br /><br />Anyway to re-emphasise that all is well in the land of OpenGL they have promoted the article about <a href="http://www.opengl.org/pipeline/article/vol003_9/">OpenGL on Vista to their frontpage</a>.  Obviously support is still not as robust as the XP implementation, but then again most drivers are lacking at the moment (due to the recency of the release).</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take Screenshots on Vista]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/03/09/take-screenshots-on-vista/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-09T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/03/09/take-screenshots-on-vista</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/kennykerr/archive/2007/01/28/window-clippings-1-5.aspx">Here</a> is a great little program for taking screenshots on Vista without the pollution of underlying windows unless you want it to.  It is called Window Clippings by Kenny Kerr.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vista and system RAM]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/03/01/vista-and-system-ram/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-01T19:26:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/03/01/vista-and-system-ram</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
There is an article <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/000688.html">here</a> about how Vista handles system memory.  It is called "Why does Vista use all my memory" by Jeff Atwood.<br /><br />Essentially all system memory is now considered a cache (using a system called SuperFetch).  This means that the amount of memory used would be as much RAM as is available to cache from the hard-drive.<br /><br />I don't know if I am completely sure it is a good idea because if a program requires a lot of memory then it has the initial lag to clear the cache in order to service memory requests.  Maybe as time goes on the technology will get better, so it may be more usable in the future.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
