<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Visual Studio 2008 | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/visual-studio-2008/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:44:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual C++ 2008 Feature Pack Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/10/visual-c-2008-feature-pack-released/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-10T20:31:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/10/visual-c-2008-feature-pack-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Good news for Windows C++ developers the update to Visual Studio 2008 <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/somasegar/archive/2008/04/07/visual-c-2008-feature-pack-shipped.aspx">has been released</a>.  This "Feature Pack" contains some of the new TR1 C++ standard library as well as a major MFC update.<br /><br />Details from the Visual C++ Team Weblog can be found <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2008/04/07/visual-c-2008-feature-pack-released.aspx">here</a> with some videos and links.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">TR1 Update</span><br /><br />The TR1 update is an integration of some more <a href="http://www.dinkumware.com/">Dinkumware</a> library functionality.  The features available are:<br />* array - Defines the container template class array and several supporting templates.<br />* functional - Defines several templates that help construct function objects, which are objects of a type that defines operator(). A function object can be a function pointer, but more typically, the object is used to store additional information that can be accessed during a function call.<br />* memory - Defines a class, an operator, and several templates that help allocate and free objects.<br />* random - Defines many random number generators.<br />* regex - Defines a template class to parse regular expressions, and several template classes and functions to search text for matches to a regular expression object.<br />* tuple - Defines a template tuple Class whose instances hold objects of varying types.<br />* type_traits - Defines templates that provide compile-time constants that give information about the properties of their type arguments.<br />* unordered_map - Defines the container template classes unordered_map and unordered_multimap and their supporting templates.<br />* unordered_set - Defines the container template classes unordered_multiset and unordered_set and their supporting templates.<br />* utility - Defines several general templates that can be used throughout the Standard Template Library.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">MFC Update</span><br /><br />The MFC Update integrates BCGSoft's libraries into the base MFC and provides masses of useful user interface constructs for native developers.  Details from the Visual C++ Weblog is <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2008/04/07/mfc-update-powered-by-bcgsoft.aspx">here</a>.<br /><br />Some of the new features are:<br />* Office 2007 Ribbon Bar:  Ribbon, Pearl, Quick Access Toolbar, Status Bar, etc.<br />* Office 2003 and XP look:  Office-style toolbars and menus, Outlook-style shortcut bar, print preview, live font picker, color picker, etc.<br />* Visual Studio look:  sophisticated docking functionality, auto hide windows, property grids, MDI tabs, tab groups, etc.<br />* Internet Explorer look:  Rebars and task panes.<br />* Vista theme support.<br />* “On the fly” menus and toolbar customization:  users can customize the running application through live drag and drop of menu items and toolbar buttons.<br />* Shell management classes:  use these classes to enumerate folders, drives and items, browse for folders and more.<br /><br /><br />You can download all this from <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=D466226B-8DAB-445F-A7B4-448B326C48E7&displaylang=en">here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2008 Feature Pack Beta]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/08/visual-studio-2008-feature-pack-beta/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-08T22:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/08/visual-studio-2008-feature-pack-beta</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Microsoft have just released the beta of the Visual Studio 2008 "Feature Pack" which is an update for the C++ portion of the environment.  The main features are substantial updates to MFC and TR1 library support.<br /><br /><span style="font-style:italic;">The VC++ 2008 MFC libraries have been extended to support creation of applications that have:<br />    * Office Ribbon style interface<br />    * Office 2007, Office 2003 and Office XP look and feel<br />    * Modern Visual Studio-style docking toolbars and panes<br />    * Fully customizable toolbars and menus<br />    * A rich set of advanced GUI controls<br />    * Advanced MDI tabs and groups<br />    * And much more!<br /><br />This feature pack also includes an implementation of TR1. Portions of TR1 are scheduled for adoption in the upcoming C++0x standard as the first major addition to the ISO 2003 standard C++ library. Our implementation includes a number of important features such as:<br />    * Smart pointers<br />    * Regular expression parsing<br />    * New containers (tuple, array, unordered set, etc)<br />    * Sophisticated random number generators<br />    * Polymorphic function wrappers<br />    * Type traits<br />    * And more!<br /><br />Note: This feature pack does not include C99 compatibility or support for special math functions.</span><br /><br />Certainly for anyone maintaining MFC based products it is a free upgrade tot he look and feel of the program with tons of advantages.<br /><br />You can <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=D466226B-8DAB-445F-A7B4-448B326C48E7&displaylang=en">download it here</a>.  Unfortunately it tries to force you to download Silverlight which I have been avoiding like the plague but the attempts to get you to install it from Microsoft are getting more aggressive.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official News On The MFC Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/11/official-news-on-mfc-update/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-11T21:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/11/official-news-on-mfc-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
http://www.blogger.com/img/gl.link.gifObviously I have been posting recently about the new native code and MFC updates that will be appearing in Visual Studio 2008.  There is now some official news on the <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/">Visual C++ Team Blog</a>.<br /><br />You can see the posts here:<br />* <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2007/11/09/announcing-a-major-mfc-update-plus-tr1-support.aspx">Announcing a major MFC update plus TR1 support</a><br />* <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2007/11/09/channel-9-pat-brenner-overview-of-new-mfc-update.aspx">Channel 9: Pat Brenner – Overview of new MFC update</a><br />* <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2007/11/09/hola-from-barcelona-and-welcome-to-a-major-mfc-update.aspx">Hola from Barcelona…and welcome to a major MFC update!</a><br />* <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/archive/2007/11/09/quick-tour-of-new-mfc-functionality.aspx">Quick Tour Of New MFC Functionality</a><br /><br />In the new year the native code improvements will be in beta and it will all be released in a service pack early next year.  It'll be interesting to see what the code available will actually be like.<br /><br />Anyway, now I'll be aiming for a change of subject...</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GUI Toolkits - MFC v9 - Visual Studio 2008 - Yet Another Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/09/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008_09/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-09T09:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/09/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008_09</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Well, as it turns out the new features for MFC in Visual Studio 2008 are actually a license of the <a href="http://www.bcgsoft.com/">BCGSoft</a> interface toolkits.  I guess this might be similar to the deal with Dinkumware for the STL implementation that Microsoft license a version of and then bolt their own things into.  Obviously it is not as good as having the actual implementation used by Microsoft in their modern products (Office 2007) but it is a start.<br /><br />There is a thread on <a href="https://forum.codejock.com/forum_posts.asp?TID=8232">Codejock here</a> explaining some of the history.  I do agree with them that Codejock has looked better than BCGSoft when I evaluated them, but I suppose the tools that are free will always win out.  Also it explains the lack of ribbon designer integration, although it is amazing MS don't have a pluggable back-end for the forms and ribbon designer.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GUI Toolkits - MFC v9 - Visual Studio 2008 - An Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/08/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-08T16:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/11/08/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I blogged a while back about the secret MFC features for VS2008 (MFC v9) <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/10/gui-toolkits-mfc-v9-visual-studio-2008.html">here</a>.  The information was going to appear at Microsoft Technet Europe 2007in a talk by Ale Contenti.<br /><br />Well, I think the talk must have now happened as there are a few posts out here on the Internet about it.<br /><br />You can read one <a href="http://blog.kalmbach-software.de/2007/11/07/mfcupdate-mfc-now-has-a-visual-manager-and-will-add-office-2007-ribbon-controls-and-many-more-features/">here</a> and another <a href="http://www.google.com/translate?u=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.m-ri.de%2Findex.php%2F2007%2F11%2F07%2Fmfc-updates-for-visual-studio-2008-and-beyond-mfcnext%2F&langpair=de|en&hl=en&ie=UTF8">translated here</a>.<br /><br />It amounts to lots of good stuff for native C++ developers on Windows:<br />* Docking windows<br />* Tabbed MDI<br />* Office 2007 theme<br />* Ribbon interface (no visual designer yet though)<br />* Lots of new controls<br />* Skins<br />* Vista specific enhancements<br />* And plenty more...<br /><br />I actually can't wait to get my hands on this and have a play, unfortunately we do have to wait until next month for a release candidate as it will be an add-on.  The interesting thing is the visual styles manager which will allow switching visual styles at runtime.<br /><br />Apparently there will be a Channel 9 video soon that should appear <a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Showforum.aspx?forumid=14&tagid=17">here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
