<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HTPC | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/htpc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T21:43:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[X-Box Media Center - For Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/05/30/x-box-media-center-for-linux/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-30T20:09:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/05/30/x-box-media-center-for-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The critically acclaimed <a href="http://www.xboxmediacenter.com/">X-Box Media Center</a> which is a HTPC program for the X-Box is planning to work on a Linux version.  Bizarrely some of X-Box Media Center inspired <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/">Media Portal</a>, the very good and comprehensive HTPC program for Windows.<br /><br />They are looking for C/C++ developers to help with the porting to another platform.  This will require substantial work to port the functionality requiring new playback engines, 2D and 3D graphics, and no doubt lots more.<br /><br />There is a thread on their forum for developers <a href="http://www.xboxmediacenter.com/forum/showthread.php?t=26097">here</a>.  There is a post on the forum for end users <a href="http://www.xboxmediacenter.com/forum/showthread.php?t=26097">here</a>.<br /><br />On their wiki the preparations are going along.  You can read this information <a href="http://www.xboxmediacenter.com/wiki/index.php?title=Linux_port_project">here</a>.<br /><br />I have the sincerest hope this is successful because with MythTV out there things will be healthy for Linux HTPC programs.  Also, it is a good thing it will be built out of open-source and free tools.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows MCE - The Codec Issue]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/11/windows-mce-codec-issue/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-11T21:14:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/11/windows-mce-codec-issue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
When I installed Windows MCE Edition I updated everything to what Windows Update offered.  This included Windows Media Player 11.  When I tried to run media centre it played nothing, not even TV.  Luckily I blamed WMP11 before anything else.<br /><br />I went in search of codecs.<br /><br />I found one particular codec pack that did the job and allows me to play DVDs and everything in my video and music folders, even spotting dolby digital.  This codec pack is The <a href="http://www.cole2k.net">Cole2K Codec Pack</a>.  A simple installer takes all the thought out of doing it which makes it even better.<br /><br />Other ones I found which I didn't use are:<br /><a href="http://www.free-codecs.com/download/K_Lite_Codec_Pack.htm">K-Lite Codec Packs</a><br /><a href="http://www.msfn.org/board/index.php?showtopic=66826">Advanced Vista Codec Pack</a><br /><br />So if you are having problems with video or music playback in Windows try one of these packages and it should ease all your worries.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows XP Media Centre Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/11/widows-xp-media-centre-edition/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-11T20:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/11/widows-xp-media-centre-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've now finally got around to installing Windows MCE on my media centre after fooling around with <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/">Media Portal</a> as my media centre software.<br /><br />My media centre is based on a cheap AOpen XC-Cube with a cheapo Sempron 2600+.  Amazingly it works pretty well the only problem being the transition animations are not too smooth occasionally when running at the highest possible resolution (1280x1024x32bpp).<br /><br />I've been quite impressed with the software.  It is much smoother to set up then the open-source ones I have used in the past, but I don't particularly want to use something because it is the path of least resistance.<br /><br />In general the smooth set up and the smooth operation has been better than I expected.  It now works much better with the MCE infra-red keyboard and control, the stand-by operation is much smoother and wake-up ability much better.  Maybe the drivers installed for MCE since it does not necessarily use the same drivers as XP Home/Pro make it more stable?<br /><br />Still after installing it you have to download one round of updates, then 78 updates, then another 13 (at least).  That takes ages - yawn.<br /><br />I'm actually quite impressed by the associated operating system - it is XP with a lick of paint and extra features.  I have no idea why Microsoft didn't use it as an opportunity to release a new version of the OS at the consumer level since MCE is only really for manufacturers.  All manufacturers seem to be using MCE ahead of XP Home anyway now.<br /><br />Overall it has been a very good experience and my wife is finding it easy to use, that is always a good yardstick.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Theatre PCs - MythTV]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/05/home-theatre-pcs-mythtv/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-05T22:35:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/05/home-theatre-pcs-mythtv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.mythtv.org">MythTV</a> is a Linux-based media centre program, but it also gives you so much more than that.  I have to say that this is better than any other media centre software out there.  Why is this?<br /><br />It has been designed from the outset to provide a client/server architecture.  This probably doesn't mean much to many people at the moment, but it is certainly the way forward.  What you have is a back-end that provides the media content, then you have front-ends that allow you to access that content.<br /><br />The simplest install is to have the back-end and front-end on the same computer, providing the same functionality as any other media system.  If you plan to have more than one front-end you have have the back-end on another computer, but both will be able to access it.  The back-end is also responsible for recording the TV and cataloguing the data, so you can stick a few TV cards in there and make simultaneous viewing and recordings.  And for your front-end you can make it as powerful or lightweight and silent as you want as you can limit the moving parts when the brute force (apart from decoding) is provided by the server.<br /><br />The real power comes from the client/server architecture, as the front-ends can be implemented in anything that you can connect to the <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV</a> protocol.  This is most apparent because it easily has a front-end for web access (meaning you can schedule your recordings remotely), there are also other smaller front-ends to the default and even a small one for Windows which is functional.  The back-end server software is pretty much rock solid because it builds on the foundations of Apache and MySQL.<br /><br />Recently version 0.20 was released with a whole raft of new functionality including OpenGL UI rendering and a more library based architecture.  You can see the rather long <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/wiki/index.php/Release_Notes_-_0.20">changelog here</a>.<br /><br />If you want to try this out you can also do this without installing it thanks to the wonders of <a href="http://www.mysettopbox.tv/knoppmyth.html">KnoppMyth</a>.  This is a <a href="http://www.knoppix.net/">Knoppix</a> based distribution on a CD/DVD with MythTV set up so you can try it out and if you like it install it.<br /><br />There is also <a href="http://swik.net/MythDora">MythDora</a> a Fedora-based MythTV distribution.  This is based on Fedora Core 4, a little out of date.<br /><br />There is an excellent resource for getting <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV</a> installed for Fedora <a href="http://wilsonet.com/mythtv/fcmyth.php">here</a>.  This is highly recommended and comprehensive.<br /><br />Also, for the Ubuntu people out there, you can use <a href="http://parker1.co.uk/mythtv_ubuntu.php">this resource</a> to get the information you need.<br /><br />Lets not forget the <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/modules.php?name=MythInstall">excellent documentation</a> and the <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page">Wiki</a>.  You can see some <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/wiki/index.php/Category:Themes">themes here</a> and some <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/modules.php?name=MythFeatures">screenshots here</a>.  Also there are thriving communities including the forums and mailing lists at MythTV itself and KnoppMyth, and there is also <a href="http://www.mythtvtalk.com/">MythTV Talk</a>.<br /><br />And here is a screenshot for the curious:<br /><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger2/5090/4314/1600/Retro.jpg"><img style="cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger2/5090/4314/320/Retro.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
As of the 12th November it is more up to date than KnoppMyth, unfortunately this post was done a week before that news update.  Certainly with an older Linux distribution and kernel surely some drivers would be missing.<br /><br />I personally would probably use http://wilsonet.com/mythtv/fcmyth.phpto get it all up and running Fedora, but I am that way inclined.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Dennis</div>
<div class='content'>
Why would you say that MythDora is out of date? Just because it's FC4? Thats nothing to go by. MythDora is more up to date than KnoppMyth.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Theatre PCs - MediaPortal]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/05/home-theatre-pcs-mediaportal/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-05T12:03:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/05/home-theatre-pcs-mediaportal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
And now for a complete change of pace...<br /><br />One thing I particularly like doing it fiddling about with home-made HTPCs (Home Theatre PCs).  I've built myself a little system for a little over £200 involving an AOpen XC-Cube.  This became necessary when we moved house and the main computer was moved away from the TV.<br /><br />I decided to use Windows for the OS for expediency's sake and as the graphics chipset on the motherboard was not well supported in Linux.  I could have gone for Windows XP MCE Edition, but I already knew of an alternative I preferred.<br /><br />Check out <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/">MediaPortal</a> for a fully featured media centre system that is fully open-source.  This project actually grew out of the well respected <a href="http://www.xboxmediacenter.de/">XBox Media Centre (XBMC)</a>.  It looks and feels great and has full compatibility with things like MCE remotes.  They've recently updated to an unstable build of 0.2.1.0 which I have found completely stable for my own uses, but I tend to only watch TV/TV programs on it.  Also, more excitingly they have started work on the TV Server project so that the TV cards and content can be hosted on a back-end server and the actual media PC can be as trimmed down as you can make it.<br /><br />There are also a variety of skins to make it look really good, a lot of which broke with version 0.2.1.0 as there were some substantial changes to the XML format.  Here is a list of some working ones:<br /><ul><li>MCE is currently missing (the one that looks very similar to Windows Media Centre Edition) but will be reinstated to the release very soon (it is probably already accessible under solution).</li><li><a href="http://forum.team-mediaportal.com/showthread.php?t=11947">MePo skins</a> - These are fantastic featuring the new mascot type character MePo.</li><li><a href="http://forum.team-mediaportal.com/showthread.php?t=12133">Simplify</a> - A bit of an understated skin.</li><li><a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/files/Download/Codecs/Replicant0.2/">Replicant</a></li><li><a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/files/Download/Skins/4:3/SimpleMP-Beta1/">SimpleMP</a></li><li><a href="http://forum.team-mediaportal.com/showthread.php?t=5212">Vista Style MCE</a></li><li>KIS - Looks incredibly impressive but I have not had a chance to download and play with it yet.  There is <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/files/Download/Skins/16:9/KISbeta/">KIS</a>, <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/files/Download/Skins/16:9/KIS/">KIS Dark</a>, and the <a href="http://www.team-mediaportal.com/files/Download/Skins/16:9/SkinSourceFiles/KISSDK/">KIS SDK</a> for plug-in pages.</li></ul>MediaPortal has coverage for emulators (I had a lot of fun with this and my arcade joystick), built-in games, weather, music, DVDs, TV, radio, films, and numerous plug-ins.  Since it is also simply an application you can install and use it on any supported PC.  It may not be the most technologically advanced or have the best architecture, but it does the job more than admirably and more importantly it is as easy to use as running the installer and following the setup wizard.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
