<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Development | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:47:23+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redmine - Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/06/03/redmine-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-03T20:40:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/06/03/redmine-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I have been playing with the project management/issue tracker <a href="http://www.redmine.org/">Redmine</a> a bit more over the past couple of days.  I have been getting more and more impressed the more I use it because it is so swift to use, by swift I don't mean it runs fast, I mean it gets work done with the minimum of fuss.<br /><br />The issue tracking system is pretty simplistic if you do a direct comparison to something like Bugzilla, but it provides the essentials.  The best bit though is the support for custom fields out of the box, so you can pretty much set up your bug report the way you want it.  You can do all the normal things as well like configuring your workflow.<br /><br />Using the listview of issue gives you a great context menu that you can use to do common actions like setting the priority, status, and completion percentage.<br /><br />The issue tracking also integrates time tracking so you can see the progress.  You have a percentage complete as well as estimated time and actual time.  The time estimations can be tagged with which sub-task took the time (like design, code and test).<br /><br />I spent a bit of time messing around with the source control integration.  I decided to try it out with a Git installation I had laying about.  In the end it is pretty simple to actually do, and it provides a simple interface with coloured diffs.  This means it becomes trivial to cross reference issues, documents, code, revisions, and more in one place.  I noticed that the commit comments get added to the reports by adding the issue number.<br /><br />The icing on the cake is that it is all wrapped in a clear and intuitive user interface.  It looks good and makes use of all the Javascript goodness that users come to expect and it actually helps to make it easy to use.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.<br> <a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> | <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/semangat-mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Semangat Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a></div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>EDavis</div>
<div class='content'>
I'm glad you are enjoying using Redmine.  I've been using it for over a year now and it's been a staple in my business ever since.<BR/><BR/>If you have any questions or ideas, I frequently read the forums at Redmine.org and would love to hear your thoughts.<BR/><BR/>Eric</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bug Databases - Redmine]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/29/bug-databases-redmine/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-29T23:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/29/bug-databases-redmine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
While on my Internet travels I found a bug database system I hadn't encounterd before called <a href="http://www.redmine.org/">Redmine</a>.  It's open-source and based on <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.org/">Ruby-On-Rails</a>, and provides much more than simply bugtracking.  It refers to itself as a project management tool as it provides enough tools to do that.<br /><br />Features include:<br />* Per project wiki and forums<br />* Issue tracking<br />* Source control integration (Subversion, CVS, Darcs, Bazaar, Mercurial, Git)<br />* Gantt chart and calendar<br />* Time tracking functionality<br />* News, documents & files management<br /><br />I did a quick test install on a Ubuntu virtual machine to see what it was like.  The user interface is really quite slick and very easy to use because it makes the most of Javascript.  Even when you have a list view you get a nice context menu to do the simple and most often done changes (priority and the suchlike).<br /><br />One of the most interesting parts I found of the system is the paradigm it uses to partition data.  You create a project and it is possible to have per-project wikis, forums, and repositories.  You can even use different source control systems per project. What makes it interesting is that you can point a project at a sub-branch of a repository, so it would be possible to have a project per branch or group of branches.  This would make it much easier to track implementations on a per-branch basis.<br /><br />With document and wiki management available it is then possible to integrate the peripheral information for a product with the items involved in actually implementing it.  With the integrated wiki you can also have your requirements and design documents easily at hand.<br /><br />I know some of this is very similar to Trac, but it is good to see another tool approaching the same space.  Some of the features like the ease of source control integration is really nice.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goings On In The Land Of Eclipse]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-19T21:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been playing around with some of the Alpha/Beta releases of <a href="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse</a>.  I haven't played around with it for quite a while but some of the advancements look really interesting.<br /><br />Currently Eclipse has <a href="http://update.eclipse.org/downloads/drops/S-3.4M7-200805020100/index.php">3.4.M7</a> is available for download.  One of the most interesting features is that the user interface now supports WPF on Vista.  The Java toolkit <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Widget_Toolkit">SWT</a> now has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Presentation_Foundation">WPF</a> back-end, you can see its resolution independence if you look at it through the Magnifier application on Windows.  Also, in general, the user interface looks much more integrated into the native platform.<br /><br />You can see a list of new and newsworthy items for Eclipse <a href="http://www.eclipsecon.com/swt/R3_3/new_and_noteworthy.html">3.3 here</a> and <a href="http://download.eclipse.org/eclipse/downloads/drops/S-3.4M3-200711012000/eclipse-news-M3.html">3.4 here</a>.<br /><br />The main reason I was trying out the new version was to give the C/C++ toolkit <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/CDT/User/NewIn50">CDT 5.0</a> a go.  Doug Schaefer has blogged about it <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2008/05/cdt-50-looks-good-now-looking-ahead.html">here</a>.<br /><br />I was just playing a little with it to see how it compared to the older version and it seems a bit faster.  It has the beginnings of some nice refactorings and templates which should make some common coding tasks a bit simpler.<br /><br />Hopefully when this all comes out <a href="http://wascana.sourceforge.net/">Wascana</a> will have a new version released with a nicely packaged C/C++ development environment for Windows.  It could make a compelling alternative to other IDEs, as well as giving you access to other great tools like PyDev (for Python), Mylyn (task and bug management), and I suppose Java as well...</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Doug Schaefer</div>
<div class='content'>
No worries. I'm working in the CDT 5.0 based-Wascana right now :)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Is Good - The Open-Source Insomniac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/11/sharing-is-good-open-source-insomniac/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-11T21:28:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/11/sharing-is-good-open-source-insomniac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.insomniacgames.com/">Insomniac Games</a> who are behind Ratchet &amp; Clank and Resistance: Fall Of Man have recently decided to start sharing knowledge.  Gaming is a notoriously secretive industry and is not well renowned for its open-ness, and Insomniac think its mad that developers keep reinvenhttp://www.blogger.com/img/gl.link.gifting the same core pieces of functionality that don't even make up the bread'n'butter of gaming.<br /><br />First up is the <a href="http://www.insomniacgames.com/tech/techpage.php">R&amp;D section on their website</a>.  This section contains presentations and papers about various subjects including graphics, gameplay, memory and performance.<br /><br />Next up is the open-source BSD-style licensed code.  The section is called the <a href="http://nocturnal.insomniacgames.com/index.php/Main_Page">Nocturnal Initiative</a> and is a wiki.  There are links to community forums which aren't busy yet.<br /><br />At the moment some of the source code available is:<br /><ul><li>C++ Delegate/Event System</li><li>Pointer to reference counted objects</li><li>Pointer to heap allocated arrays</li><li>Endian conversion code</li><li>Insertion ordered std::set</li><li>Reversible key and value std::map</li><li>Interprocess Communication</li><ul><li>      Fast non-blocking message-based design</li><li>      Works over BSD-style sockets (TCP) or Named Pipes</li><li>Windows platform included, additional platforms are easily added</li></ul><li>Debugging Helpers</li><ul><li>      PDB-based symbol information querying</li><li>      Capture stacks within your program making heap object tracking and leak debugging easier</li><li>      Give your application automatic crash reports dispatched via email that contain handy user/machine informaton, call stack, and memory page allocation stats</li></ul><li>Console Output Manager</li><ul><li>      Log console output to one or more trace files</li><li>      Color code the console output based on Error/Warning/Debug print statements</li><li>Throttle output verbosity (configured via command line arg or environment variable)</li><li>      Outline nested stages of processing performed by your application (for builders/exporters)</li><li>      Augment crash reports with the current outline state of your application (very useful for tracking down new crash bugs)</li></ul><li>Instrumenting Profiler</li><ul><li>      Cross platform (Windows and PS3 currently)</li><li>      Macro-instrumented stack timer based profiler</li><li>      Concise profile report printed out at program exit</li><li>      Logs instance data out to human readable log file (Profile Analyzer is in development)</li></ul><li>C++ Reflection</li><ul><li>      Instrument your application classes and register them with the type registry</li><li>      Can serialize object instances to XML or our (faster) custom binary format</li><li>      Flexible parsing mechanics allow you to read in old versions of your class</li><li>      Handles renaming member variables as well as changing member type (within reasonable limits)</li><li>      Supports serializing std::vector, std::set, and std::map containers with primitives or pointers to other reflect objects</li><li>  Supports serializing enum and bitfield members using string representation (supports reordering enum elements)</li><li>      Provides for automatic object comparison and cloning</li><li>      Implements introspection using a visitor interface</li></ul></ul><br />Some of it looks pretty good.  I hope this means that there is more sharing of C++ code which is always a good thing, maybe even some of the libraries could be Boost-ified...</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lucasarts - The Good Old Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/13/lucasarts-good-old-days/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-13T21:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/13/lucasarts-good-old-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Now I am 30 I can get away with saying things were so much better in the olden days.  Actually, no that is not even vaguely true, there is always probably the same good to crap ratio, but the marketing of the crap means you have to dig a little deeper and smarter.<br /><br />Anyway in the olden days Lucasarts the gaming arm of all things Star Wars was actually astoundingly good at making games.  They had the best and brightest and created some of the most unforgettable experiences a person could have on their computer.  Their adventure games were masterclasses for scripting and game echanics.<br /><br />Anyway on to the point of this post - some linkage - two great articles about Lucsart classics, from the very beginning and the very end of their work in adventure games:<br />* <a href="http://www.escapistmagazine.com/articles/view/issues/issue_139/2994-Walk-Don-t-Run">Grim Fandango</a> - Walk Don't Run<br />* <a href="http://www.mixnmojo.com/features/read.php?article=maniacmansion">Maniac Mansion</a> - Lucasarts Secret history<br /><br />And also another completely unrelated gaming article is the excellent retrospective of a game developer starting his commercial career with Donkey Kong on the Atari platform.  Check out the <a href="http://www.dadhacker.com/blog/?p=987">post here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
