<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Firefox | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/firefox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-20T22:54:46+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 3 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/06/18/firefox-3-released/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-18T10:32:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/06/18/firefox-3-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Go get it here:<br /><br /><br /><a href="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/node&id=0&t=264"><img border="0" alt="Download Day" title="Download Day" src="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/files/images/affiliates_banners/dday_badge_fox.png"/></a><br /><br /><br />Have a little read on how to make it even better for the Mac <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2008/05/firefox-3-on-mac.html">here</a>.<br /><br /><br /><a href="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/node&id=0&t=309"><img border="0" alt="Firefox 3" title="Firefox 3" src="http://sfx-images.mozilla.org/affiliates/Buttons/firefox3/468x60.png"/></a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Si</div>
<div class='content'>
Hi G,<BR/><BR/>Got is last night on my home and work PC's loving most of the changes.<BR/><BR/>Not so keen on the "awesome bar" but have disabled that. <BR/><BR/>For the most part just the speed improvement is worth the upgrade alone.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 3 On The Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/18/firefox-3-on-mac/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-18T20:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/18/firefox-3-on-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been using Firefox 3 on the Mac for the past month so I thought I'd share some of my experiences when using it.  There release candidate download page is <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/all-rc.html">here</a>.<br /><br />The reason I didn't start using it beforehand was because I was waiting for a supported version of the <a href="http://www.delicious.com">Del.icio.us</a> bookmarks add-on as it has become indespensible to me.  You can get this <a href="http://blog.delicious.com/blog/2008/04/firefox-3-delicious-and-you.html">here</a>.<br /><br />I run a few add-ons to make it look more integrated with Mac OSX:<br />* <a href="http://en.design-noir.de/mozilla/locationbar2/">Locationbar 2</a> for improving the recognition of URLs.<br />* <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1951">Fission</a> for the progress in the URL field like Safari.<br />* <a href="http://www.takebacktheweb.org/">GrApple Delicious (Blue)</a> theme which looks very good (and integrated on the Mac).<br />* And don't forget <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1865">AdBlock Plus</a> whichever platform you are running on!<br /><br />With all of those add-ons working (you can also force add-ons to work by using the <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/6543">Nightly Tester Tools</a>) I was ready to use Firefox 3.  For a Beta (and now the Release Candidate) it is amazingly stable.<br /><br />The entire program is much more responsive and lighter on the system resources.  The integration and look and feel (with the add-ons) is excellent, although I would prefer if spell-checking with edit fields to be on by default (although there is a hack <a href="http://www.osxdaily.com/2007/06/06/enable-spell-checking-in-firefox-text-input-fields/">here</a>).<br /><br />In general it is a large step forward although I am not using the biggest new feature - the bookmarks replacement "Places".  As usual though the major feather in Firefox's cap is the add-ons and once you have them you find it impossible to use anything else.<br /><br />Also, I am using it on Windows Vista at work and it is fast, responsive and looks much better, although I would prefer not to have the blue tinge to the window.  I'd recommend upgrading now because once you've tried 3 you can't go back.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
