<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: OSX | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/osx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:26:22+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DisplayLink for Mac OSX]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/31/displaylink-for-mac-osx/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-31T20:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/31/displaylink-for-mac-osx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Something work related for a change...  As you can see from my profile I work for <a href="http://www.displaylink.com">DisplayLink</a> where we make USB display technology.  Most people can't believe that it will be very good, but whenever anyone sees one of our docks or adapters in action are impressed by the quality and the ease of use.<br /><br />Here at <a href="http://www.displaylink.com">DisplayLink</a> we have just released the Beta version of our Mac OSX software.  This means you can now use our USB displays on Mac - which I imagine could be very nice for the MacBook Air if the monitor has an integrated USB hub.<br /><br />You can get the Beta drivers <a href="http://www.displaylink.com/mac_beta_drivers.html">here</a>.  The general download page is <a href="http://www.displaylink.com/downloads.html">here</a>.  The Mac team have done a great job on this and it looks very impressive when you see it going.  As it is a beta it is not perfect, but it is very functional and robust.<br /><br />I've installed it on my MacBook Pro now, but I forgot to bring anything home to actually test it - duh!</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.<br> <a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> | <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/semangat-mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Semangat Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a></div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>MostlyGeek</div>
<div class='content'>
Any idea when the full version of the drivers will be out?</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>DVD e CD</div>
<div class='content'>
Hello. This post is likeable, and your blog is very interesting, congratulations :-). I will add in my blogroll =). If possible gives a last there on my blog, it is about the <A HREF="http://dvd-e-cd.blogspot.com" REL="nofollow">DVD e CD</A>, I hope you enjoy. The address is http://dvd-e-cd.blogspot.com. A hug.<A HREF="5765827617" REL="nofollow"></A></div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NeoOffice 2.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/neooffice-21/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-22T19:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/neooffice-21</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
In the <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/01/mac-osx.html">previous post</a> I mentioned <a href="http://www.neooffice.org">NeoOffice</a> - the Mac-based version of <a href="http://www.openoffice.org">OpenOffice</a>.<br /><br />In the first quarter 2007 there are plans to release version 2.1.  This is going to integrate the changes from OpenOffice 2.0->2.1, which includes new scripting and lots of improvements.  Not only that it will also have support for Office 2007 documents, and execution of VBA scripts in Excel documents.<br /><br />Overall it looks like NeoOffice is pressing ahead with substantial improvements and features.  It's good to see that Mac OSX has an accomplished office suite outside of Office for Mac.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Conficio</div>
<div class='content'>
I believe <a href="http://openoffice.screencast-tutorials.com/index">Plan-B for OpenOffice.org should be helpful for NeoOffice users</a> as well. <a hef="http://openoffice.screencast-tutorials.com/auth/register">Register and try it out</a> and let me know.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OSX]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/mac-osx/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-22T19:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/mac-osx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I'm depressed as today, I had an extended demo of a MacBook Pro.  One of the guys at work has just bought one, and now I want one...<br /><br />It is astonishing simply how good OSX is.  During the demo I saw how much it works like the way I want to use a computer.  When people who have used it say how good it is they are not exaggerating and don't have an axe to grind, they just have a computer that makes their life easier.<br /><br />The thing I noticed most about it is that MDI is alive and well.  It's not like the Windows MDI where the application encapsulates the sub projects, the operating system in OSX does the heavy lifting.  With this it also makes it much more structured and intuitive.  I can imagine working with loads of Photoshop documents and text documents at once and it all being being intuitive.  It is possible to see all the documents open at once with a zooming out style view, and it is also possible to see all the documents for a particular application.  It may not look as 3D <br /><br />Programs start very quickly and stay memory resident for fast access if necessary.  It is always clear what is going on and the user interface does is always responsive.<br /><br />All of this and I haven't mentioned how good it looks.  It has lots of great touches in the UI but none of them take over or clutter the display.  Screenshots dn't do it justice - you simply have to see it in the flesh.<br /><br />One great bit of software for OSX is <a href="http://www.neooffice.org/">NeoOffice</a> which is OpenOffice in Mac clothing.  It integrates really well into the way OSX works.  All developers involved deserve kudos for making OpenOffice into NeoOffice which I think is actually an improvement.<br /><br />One bit I wanted to see was X-Code for OSX development since I had heard so much about it.  Unfortunately it is not installed by default.<br /><br />Now I have to go off and save lots of money.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
