<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Router | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/router/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T22:32:51+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[blog@fragmentedmemory.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wireless Routers and the Linksys WRT54G]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/10/02/wireless-routers-and-linksys-wrt54g/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-02T21:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/10/02/wireless-routers-and-linksys-wrt54g</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
My dad gave me a Linksys Wireless router (WRT54G) and it looks ug-leeee, so I never used it and bought a more stylish looking one which turned out not to work properly to the point I got so annoyed I threw it away.<br /><br />So I dug out the WRT54G and plugged it in.  It worked flawlessly until today when my two router network decided to eat itself.  Eventually after much resetting I got it all up and running again, but I discovered that with heavy network traffic like P2P (and probably my surfing habits) it can crash due to keeping a record of everything for five days.<br /><br />A quick websearch lead me to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WRT54G">Wikipedia Article on the Linksys WRT54G</a> and reading that I realised exactly what I had.  The company had opened up the firmware and there were a variety of open source versions available.  I then read this <a href="http://www.utorrent.com/faq.php#Special_note_for_users_with_Linksys_WRT54G_GL_GS_routers">FAQ for utorrent</a> where it describes what firmware it recommends and how to avoid overloading the router.  Never being afraid of destroying hardware I installed <a href="http://www.thibor.co.uk/">HyperWRT Thibor</a> on the router (there is a decent <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HyperWRT">Wikipedia page for HyperWRT</a> as well).  Once it rebooted I saw how many extra features are in there now.  Needless to say I am buying only Linksys routers from now on...</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
