<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apple | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:26:22+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/06/iphone-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-06T20:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/06/iphone-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
After nearly a decade of avoiding having a mobile phone the iPhone was the device that made me change my mind.  It is a great device that means I use my laptop a lot less because I can surf the 'Net and get my imap gmail on it in a very seamless fashion.<br /><br />Today Apple announced the iPhone SDK (the website has completely crashed for me....).  It will give a whole new ease of life to an already excellent product.  One of the greatest aspects of the iPhone is that it is constantly updated with new features like a full computer.<br /><br />There is a comprehensive <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/06/live-from-apples-iphone-press-conference/">write-up on Engadget</a> and <a href="http://arstechnica.com/journals/apple.ars/2008/03/06/developers-licking-their-fingers-over-cocoa-touch-iphone-sdk">Ars Technica</a> of all the announcements today including proper Exchange support.<br /><br />The SDK gives access via Objective-C to the OS features.  You get access to the accelerometers and multi-touch when writing your apps.  XCode provides the environment to develop in and there is an iPhone simulator. The features you have access to are:<br />* Keychain<br />* Bonjour<br />* SQLite<br />* Core Location<br />* Quicktime media layer<br />* Core Audio<br />* Core Image<br />* Core Animation<br />* PDF rendering<br />* OpenAL<br />* OpenGL ES<br /><br />The games look pretty damn good on the iPhone fromt he presentation from Super Monkey Ball to Spore to the specially designed Touch Fighter.  It looks like a Wii style changing of the game by using the advantages that the device offers rather than dwelling on what is now missing in comparison to gaming systems.<br /><br />Also the apps created will be distributed by the App Store that will be run by Apple.  If you develop free or open-source apps Apple will host them and distribute them for free.<br /><br />Also there is a leak of the BBC iPlayer for the iPhone mentioned in <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/06/live-from-apples-iphone-press-conference/comments/10866456/">this comment</a> on Engadget.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Free Mac Applications]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/30/useful-free-mac-applications/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-30T20:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/01/30/useful-free-mac-applications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I'm tight, if there is a free tool to do something I will find it.  It is a bit harder work to find those applications when you use a Mac, but I have over my time using my Macbook Pro found plenty of stuff to help me get full use out of my computer.  So I thought I would share them:<br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.adiumx.com/">Adium</a> - Instant messaging with the GAIM base.</li><li><a href="http://metaquark.de/appfresh/">AppFresh</a> - Make sure that installed programs are up to date.</li><li><a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a> - Edit audio files (I used it to make iPhone ringtones).</li><li><a href="http://www.bean-osx.com/">Bean</a> - Simple and easy to use document editing.</li><li><a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/chamonix/">Chamonix</a> - A CHM reader for OSX.</li><li><a href="http://projects.digitalwaters.net/index.php?q=cocopad">Cocopad</a> - A simple scribbler application.</li><li><a href="http://cord.sourceforge.net/">CoRD</a> - Connect to other computers using the MS remote desktop protocol.</li><li><a href="http://www.blocksoft.net/docker.html">Docker</a> - Lots of settings for the dock on Leopard.</li><li><a href="http://eclipse.org">Eclipse</a> - The ubiquitous platform for IDEs.</li><li><a href="http://getfirefox.com">Firefox</a> - Because I love the plug-ins.  I'll doa post about them another time to geta more integrated Firefox (could be moot with v3.0).</li><li><a href="http://earth.google.com/">Google Earth</a> - Because i wanted to see old maps wrapped around the globe.</li><li><a href="http://toolbar.google.com/gmail-helper/notifier_mac.html">Google Notifier</a> - Keep an eye on your Google inbox.</li><li><a href="http://gridwars.marune.de/">Gridwars</a> - Free game allegedly like Geometry Wars.</li><li><a href="http://handbrake.fr/">Handbrake</a> - Rip movies to your desired format.</li><li><a href="http://www.inkscape.org/">Inkscape</a> - Vector drawing.</li><li><a href="http://www.macports.org/">MacPorts</a> - Package manager for thousands of open-source programs.  I have mentioned <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/07/great-free-software-macports.html">this before</a>.<br /></li><li><a href="http://www.mactheripper.org/">MacTheRipper</a> - DVD ripping.</li><li><a href="http://sbooth.org/Max/">Max</a> - CD ripping software.</li><li><a href="http://www.neooffice.org">NeoOffice</a> - OpenOffice integrated Aqua style.</li><li><a href="http://www.titanium.free.fr/pgs2/english/download.html">Onyx</a> - More settings for your Mac!</li><li><a href="http://perian.org/">Perian</a> - Loads of codecs for OSX.<br /></li><li><a href="http://opensword.org/Pixen/">Pixen</a> - Simple art package.</li><li><a href="http://porticus.alittledrop.com/">Porticus</a> - Great Cocoa front-end for MacPorts.</li><li><a href="http://www.fadingred.org/senuti/">Senuti</a> - Get music from your iPod back to your computer.</li><li><a href="http://www.lachoseinteractive.net/en/community/subversion/svnx/features/">SvnX</a> - Graphical front-end for Subversion.</li><li><a href="http://scplugin.tigris.org/">scplugin</a> - TortoiseSVN style integration for the Mac.</li><li><a href="http://www.bresink.de/osx/TinkerTool.html">TinkerTool</a> - More settings for the Mac.</li><li><a href="http://www.videolan.org/vlc/">VLC</a> - Great open-source video player.</li></ul>I tend to prefer open-source to free in most instances, and MacPorts (with Porticus) gives so much that it deserves more than a one line description...  oh well ;)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/06/21/back-to-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-21T18:55:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/06/21/back-to-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
There has been no blogging for a couple of weeks because I was on holiday in America, then ill.  But now it is time to get back to blogging since plenty has happened in the world of computers during my break.  I have some emails to reply to from the blog and I will get around to those over the next few days.<br /><br />The best thing about going to America was to get a nice new Macbook Pro - one of the new revisions with the LED backlight.  The model I got was the bottom of the range 2.2GHz Core 2 Duo (4MB cache) 15 inch version, which now comes with 120GB of hard drive.<br /><br />The LED backlight has substantially increased the battery life of the Macbook Pros and the picture quality is astounding.  I got the matte look screen as it provides much better colour tones at a lesser intensity.<br /><br />And OS X - I should never have waited this long to switch to anything other than Windows.  It is astoundingly good.<br /><br />There will probably be more Mac content on the blog in the future but I will still be using Windows in other places so I will still be interested in development on that platform, but probably with a more cross-platform slant.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
I haven't got around to installing Ubuntu yet.  If it is painless I might give it a go.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Frabcus</div>
<div class='content'>
Yep - I recently got a MacBook (not pro) as my new laptop. The hardware is not only better designed, but it is also CHEAPER than equivalent spec PCs.<BR/><BR/>And it runs Ubuntu just as well!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NeoOffice 2.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/neooffice-21/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-22T19:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/neooffice-21</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
In the <a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/01/mac-osx.html">previous post</a> I mentioned <a href="http://www.neooffice.org">NeoOffice</a> - the Mac-based version of <a href="http://www.openoffice.org">OpenOffice</a>.<br /><br />In the first quarter 2007 there are plans to release version 2.1.  This is going to integrate the changes from OpenOffice 2.0->2.1, which includes new scripting and lots of improvements.  Not only that it will also have support for Office 2007 documents, and execution of VBA scripts in Excel documents.<br /><br />Overall it looks like NeoOffice is pressing ahead with substantial improvements and features.  It's good to see that Mac OSX has an accomplished office suite outside of Office for Mac.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Conficio</div>
<div class='content'>
I believe <a href="http://openoffice.screencast-tutorials.com/index">Plan-B for OpenOffice.org should be helpful for NeoOffice users</a> as well. <a hef="http://openoffice.screencast-tutorials.com/auth/register">Register and try it out</a> and let me know.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OSX]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/mac-osx/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-22T19:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/22/mac-osx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I'm depressed as today, I had an extended demo of a MacBook Pro.  One of the guys at work has just bought one, and now I want one...<br /><br />It is astonishing simply how good OSX is.  During the demo I saw how much it works like the way I want to use a computer.  When people who have used it say how good it is they are not exaggerating and don't have an axe to grind, they just have a computer that makes their life easier.<br /><br />The thing I noticed most about it is that MDI is alive and well.  It's not like the Windows MDI where the application encapsulates the sub projects, the operating system in OSX does the heavy lifting.  With this it also makes it much more structured and intuitive.  I can imagine working with loads of Photoshop documents and text documents at once and it all being being intuitive.  It is possible to see all the documents open at once with a zooming out style view, and it is also possible to see all the documents for a particular application.  It may not look as 3D <br /><br />Programs start very quickly and stay memory resident for fast access if necessary.  It is always clear what is going on and the user interface does is always responsive.<br /><br />All of this and I haven't mentioned how good it looks.  It has lots of great touches in the UI but none of them take over or clutter the display.  Screenshots dn't do it justice - you simply have to see it in the flesh.<br /><br />One great bit of software for OSX is <a href="http://www.neooffice.org/">NeoOffice</a> which is OpenOffice in Mac clothing.  It integrates really well into the way OSX works.  All developers involved deserve kudos for making OpenOffice into NeoOffice which I think is actually an improvement.<br /><br />One bit I wanted to see was X-Code for OSX development since I had heard so much about it.  Unfortunately it is not installed by default.<br /><br />Now I have to go off and save lots of money.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
