<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Eclipse | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/eclipse/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T21:43:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goings On In The Land Of Eclipse]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-19T21:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been playing around with some of the Alpha/Beta releases of <a href="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse</a>.  I haven't played around with it for quite a while but some of the advancements look really interesting.<br /><br />Currently Eclipse has <a href="http://update.eclipse.org/downloads/drops/S-3.4M7-200805020100/index.php">3.4.M7</a> is available for download.  One of the most interesting features is that the user interface now supports WPF on Vista.  The Java toolkit <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Widget_Toolkit">SWT</a> now has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Presentation_Foundation">WPF</a> back-end, you can see its resolution independence if you look at it through the Magnifier application on Windows.  Also, in general, the user interface looks much more integrated into the native platform.<br /><br />You can see a list of new and newsworthy items for Eclipse <a href="http://www.eclipsecon.com/swt/R3_3/new_and_noteworthy.html">3.3 here</a> and <a href="http://download.eclipse.org/eclipse/downloads/drops/S-3.4M3-200711012000/eclipse-news-M3.html">3.4 here</a>.<br /><br />The main reason I was trying out the new version was to give the C/C++ toolkit <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/CDT/User/NewIn50">CDT 5.0</a> a go.  Doug Schaefer has blogged about it <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2008/05/cdt-50-looks-good-now-looking-ahead.html">here</a>.<br /><br />I was just playing a little with it to see how it compared to the older version and it seems a bit faster.  It has the beginnings of some nice refactorings and templates which should make some common coding tasks a bit simpler.<br /><br />Hopefully when this all comes out <a href="http://wascana.sourceforge.net/">Wascana</a> will have a new version released with a nicely packaged C/C++ development environment for Windows.  It could make a compelling alternative to other IDEs, as well as giving you access to other great tools like PyDev (for Python), Mylyn (task and bug management), and I suppose Java as well...</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Doug Schaefer</div>
<div class='content'>
No worries. I'm working in the CDT 5.0 based-Wascana right now :)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse CDT For Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/02/eclipse-cdt-for-windows/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-02T08:35:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/02/eclipse-cdt-for-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The <a href="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse</a> IDE (which is cross-platform and designed to have plug-ins written for) has a good C++ module called <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/cdt/">CDT</a> (C/C++ Development Toolkit).<br /><br />Recently version <a href="http://help.eclipse.org/help33/index.jsp?topic=/org.eclipse.cdt.doc.user/concepts/cdt_c_whatsnew.htm">4.0 was released</a> in tandem with the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/org/press-release/20070627_europarelease.php">Europa release of Eclipse</a>.  It has been massively improved and gives much better Windows support.<br /><br />Now the lead developer of CDT, Doug Schaefer, has started a new project called <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/cdt-windows">CDT For Windows</a> which aims to make it obscenely simple to install and run Eclipse+CDT on Windows.  Check out <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2007/06/introducing-cdt-for-windows.html">his post announcing this here</a>.  This is a great step forward and I hope this works out well.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IDE - Eclipse CDT]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/12/17/ide-eclipse-cdt/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-17T21:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/12/17/ide-eclipse-cdt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</a> is a popular development platform, kind of more than an IDE.  It is based solely around plug-ins and provides a good development environment.  At the moment most of its strength is the Java development and its use for embedded systems (see my previous article about SunSPOTs - that used the Eclipse IDE for remote debugging.<br /><br />One of the projects within it I keep an eye on is the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/cdt/">CDT</a> project which is a plug-in for C/C++ aiming to be as strong as the Java development.  At the moment it is used a lot for the embedded space, but they want to extend it even further and challenge the <br />Visual Studio IDEs.<br /><br />The guy heading up the CDT project Doug Schaefer has been blogging about the progress of the project for a while.  In the CDT 4.0 roadmap the plan is to use the Windows SDK and have integrated debugging and the suchlike.  His most recent post <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2006/12/migrating-from-visualc-to-cdt.html">"Migrating From Visual C++ to CDT"</a> shows the progress the project is making.  It is always great to have alternatives and Eclipse certainly could help along that route.  Part of the plan is also to add C# support as well from the Windows SDK.  At the moment I would not recommend using CDT in lieu of VS2005 for Windows application development but if your toolchain is make based you may find this a better alternative.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
