<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gcc | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/gcc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T21:43:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MinGW GCC 4.2 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/mingw-gcc-42-released/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-09T21:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/mingw-gcc-42-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Well, it's not a full release, but a beta type release.  <a href="http://www.mingw.org">MinGW</a> has <a href="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.gnu.mingw.user/23358">released GCC 4.2</a> on Windows is now available.<br /><br />The first proper version 4 release will be 4.3 when it is released.  This is because Windows will become a properly supported platform as historically MinGW have done loads of work making it work on Windows.<br /><br />The jump from 3.4 to the version 4 codebase will provide massive improvements including OpenMP for multithreading, better and more powerful optimisations and better language support.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MinGW GCC and all that great stuff]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/05/10/mingw-gcc-and-all-that-great-stuff/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-10T20:32:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/05/10/mingw-gcc-and-all-that-great-stuff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of the most overlooked programs out there is GCC - <a href="http://gcc.gnu.org/">The Gnu Compiler Collection</a> - a vast array of development tools that are truly free to use unencumbered.<br /><br />It provides a suite of compilers from Fortran, to Java, to C++.<br /><br />At the moment for Windows unless you use Cygwin (not recommended) you will be using <a href="http://www.mingw.org">MinGW</a> which is currently at version 3.4.5, some way behind the version available on Unix systems (which is in 4.2 prerelease).  The good news is that once gcc 4.2 is released it will be released for MinGW, which should mean lots of good improvements, from standards compliance to OpenMP to speed ups from new optimisations.<br /><br />Obviously it does not only target specific OSes, but it also targets different platforms including 64-bit.<br /><br />Admittedly it is not as fast the the Microsoft compilers, but maybe it will get there.  One worry is that Microsoft will lose interest in their compilers for native code as they go further and further down the .NET route.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
