<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Source Control | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/source-control/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:26:22+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git For Windows - msysgit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/10/git-for-windows-msysgit/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-10T19:04:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/04/10/git-for-windows-msysgit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Today I finally got a chance to install <a href="http://code.google.com/p/msysgit/">msysgit</a> - the Git port for Windows using <a href="http://www.mingw.org">MinGW</a>.<br /><br />I was extremely impressed with the painless install and the ease of integration (into the shell context menu and the commandline).  The installer size is a trim 8Mb so it is a quick download to try out.<br /><br />The main thing I have tried out at the moment is the newly functioning (for Windows) Subversion bridge.  The git-svn import seems fairly speedy even on Windows and works seamlessly.  It is interesting how efficiently the data gets stored inteh repository as well, and the possibility of reconstructing information that has been lost due to file moves and other lossy operations in Subversion.<br /><br />Git-GUI also works.  Obviously it does not look spiffy and shiny but presents the information you need, and access to the operations you need (on a basic level).<br /><br />I would say Git For Windows is very close to being "ready" and providing you are not in need of the more difficult corner cases it is ready for production use.  The guys working on it have done a great job.<br /><br />Now all we need is their version of TortoiseSVN to take off called <a href="http://repo.or.cz/w/git-cheetah.git/">git-cheetah</a> (which probably is getting easier thanks to some of the Tortoises sharing code now to do with displaying overlays).<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Git Is The New Unix</span><br /><br />There is a great article about what Git really means as a platform.  You can read it <a href="http://www.advogato.org/person/apenwarr/diary/371.html">here</a>.<br /><br />This kind of opened my eyes to how Git differs from not only other source control systems, but other distributed source control systems.  I recommend giving it a quick read.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.<br> <a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> | <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/semangat-mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Semangat Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a></div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>dwks</div>
<div class='content'>
Good to know that git works quite well on Windows -- I've decided to try a distributed version control system, and one of the things that was preventing me from choosing git was its (lack of) Windows support.<BR/><BR/>The article you linked to is a great read, thanks. (By the way, it's called "Git is the /next/ UNIX", not "new".)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Source Control - Subversion and TortoiseSVN 1.5]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/19/source-control-subversion-and/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-19T20:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/19/source-control-subversion-and</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
There is no official release date for Subversion 1.5 although Alpha 2 is currently available.  I thought I'd post about the upcoming features that will be making their way into the release.  there is also a little bit at the end about TortoiseSVN 1.5 features.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Merge Tracking</span><br /><br />The most important feature in the upcoming 1.5.  The initial concept is based on svnmerge.py but has gone far beyond that and is fully integrated into the repository format.  This means it will be possible to see which revisions have yet to be merged or have already been done.  For people with complex branching or regular merging it should be an indispensable feature.<br /><br />Interesting links about it are <a href="http://blogs.open.collab.net/svn/2007/05/the_subversion__1.html">here</a>, <a href="http://blogs.open.collab.net/svn/2007/11/what-about-bran.html">here</a>, and <a href="http://blogs.open.collab.net/svn/2007/11/branching-strat.html">here</a>.  The functional spec is available <a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/merge-tracking/func-spec.html">here</a>.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Sparse Checkouts</span><br /><br />This allows for checking out portions of a larger repository.  This means it is possible to specify the depth that the operations take into the directory structure.<br /> <br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Conflict Resolution</span><br /><br />There are improvements to the conflict resolution for merges.  It is now possible to use the command-line to perform the resolution and a better interface for graphical clients.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Changelists</span><br /><br />It is possible to work on several sets of files on a single working copy.  You can associate those files together with a name in order to work on more than one problem in a single working copy.  I really needed this feature at work today trying to do more than one thing in a single working copy.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Externals Improvements</span><br /><br />The improvements allow svn:externals to be pegged at a revision.  Also they can use relative paths from the current directory (that will be really good in some instances with external deliverables) and if you use externals it makes managing a code tree much easier because it treats it like it is part of the current code tree.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Copy/Rename Improvements</span><br /><br />There is an improvement in the behaviour on copy/renaming of files (not currently directories until version 1.6) by the client trying to be smarter.  If a file has been renamed/copied then rather than the server sending the whole new file it does the copy operation so you should not lose the changes that had been made to the old file.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">TortoiseSVN 1.5</span><br /><br />This should be released not long after the main Subversion 1.5 release.  The major changes will be the user interface work for merge tracking, changesets, and sparse checkouts.  There are some other features that will be part of the 1.5 release:<br />* Client side hook scripts – You can run some scripts before or after committing - this should help people create better processes.<br />* If a program has done some file operations like renaming and deleting without using the Subversion interface (drag-right-click) then it is possible to fix the file relationships in the UI.  This would be quite useful to inte3grate as an external tool in Visual Studio.<br />* Repository browser now has a two pane look like Windows Explorer with a tree-view and list of files.  Apparently it is much faster.<br />* A new merge wizard rather than the dialog which improves the workflow for merging.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.<br> <a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> | <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/semangat-mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Semangat Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a></div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Good Bazaar Reading]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/18/some-good-bazaar-reading/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-18T20:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/18/some-good-bazaar-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Some good articles about Bazaar can be read here:<br />* Part 1 - <a href="http://ianclatworthy.wordpress.com/2007/06/21/version-control-the-future-is-adaptive/">Version Control : The Future Is Adaptive</a><br />* Part 2 - <a href="http://ianclatworthy.wordpress.com/2007/07/02/it-takes-a-community-to-raise-great-software/">It Takes A Community To Raise Great Software</a><br />* Part 3 - <a href="http://ianclatworthy.wordpress.com/2007/07/11/wanted-rock-solid-version-control/">Wanted : Rock Solid Version Control</a><br />* Part 4 - <a href="http://ianclatworthy.wordpress.com/2007/07/18/version-control-plug-ins-vs-toolkits/">Version Control: Plug-ins Versus Toolkits</a><br /><br />The blogger Ian Clatworthy does work on Bazaar so it obviously has a slant that way, but he makes good points and knows what he is on about.  Or maybe I am biased now after being pleasantly surprised by Bazaar...</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bazaar and Visual Studio Integration]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/16/bazaar-and-visual-studio-integration/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-16T22:47:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/16/bazaar-and-visual-studio-integration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The <a href="http://bazaar-vcs.org/">Bazaar</a> distributed source control system has some Google Summer Of Code Projects.  One of which is the Visual Studio integration and recently there has been a status update on the mailing list talking about progress - <a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/bazaar/2007q3/027836.html">read it here</a>.<br /><br />I think the distributed source control system that catches on will probably be the one which manages to get together the best external tools and UI.  Bazaar seems to have a few projects that are actively developed that could deal with that and make it quite a contender.<br /><br />Part of the development for this project though is wrapping the API in a Microsoft embeddable way.  An interesting approach but I can think of a few other routes.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Revision Control And APIs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/16/distributed-revision-control-and-apis/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-16T22:33:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/07/16/distributed-revision-control-and-apis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of the reasons blogging has been quiet the past week or so is I've been fiddling about with some coding.<br /><br />I've been trying out <a href="http://www.wxpython.org">wxPython</a> and using it as an interface to a distributed source control system.  It's purely experimental, but it did show me some deficiencies and strengths in some of the ones available.<br /><br />Here is what I learnt though...  wxPython is a great way of hacking together a coherent UI fast, I am still relatively inexperienced in Python and wxPython but the resources out there on the Internet are very useful.<br /><br />As for the source control systems...  First I tried out <a href="http://www.selenic.com/mercurial/">Mercurial</a>, but I am really struggling with the API and trying to write extensions.  This is mainly due to the lack of documentation, and a lot of current tools like <a href="http://qct.sourceforge.net/">Qct</a> simply parse the commandline.  I did work out some of the parts of the API to wrap, but I found it hard going with limited Python knowledge and a lack of comments.<br /><br />The other system I tried was <a href="http://bazaar-vcs.org/">Bazaar</a> which I found a very different experience.  The API is excellently documented and the plug-in API is excellent.  Admittedly the criticism levelled at this source contrl system is the speed, but it gets so much right.  It is built on a solid foundation of correctness and the barrier for entry is lowered thanks to the excellent documentation.  I managed o get a working status dialog up and running in a very short period of time (although admittedly I got sidetracked afterwards fiddling around with wxPython).<br /><br />One of the reasons I was using wxPython is that it looks native on my Macbook Pro as a lot of the available UIs are GTK based meaning they look pretty bad on OS X.  Also I wanted to try it out on Windows which meant it looked pretty good on that platform as well.<br /><br />Hopefully I can find the time to tidy some of this code up into a reusable form and actually see something like at least the status and commit dialogs through to completion.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Matt Doar</div>
<div class='content'>
I found that the Mercurial book was pretty good when it came to writing plugins. That and looking at the source for other plugins.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
