<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: IDE | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/ide/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T21:43:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goings On In The Land Of Eclipse]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-19T21:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/05/19/goings-on-in-land-of-eclipse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been playing around with some of the Alpha/Beta releases of <a href="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse</a>.  I haven't played around with it for quite a while but some of the advancements look really interesting.<br /><br />Currently Eclipse has <a href="http://update.eclipse.org/downloads/drops/S-3.4M7-200805020100/index.php">3.4.M7</a> is available for download.  One of the most interesting features is that the user interface now supports WPF on Vista.  The Java toolkit <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Widget_Toolkit">SWT</a> now has a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Presentation_Foundation">WPF</a> back-end, you can see its resolution independence if you look at it through the Magnifier application on Windows.  Also, in general, the user interface looks much more integrated into the native platform.<br /><br />You can see a list of new and newsworthy items for Eclipse <a href="http://www.eclipsecon.com/swt/R3_3/new_and_noteworthy.html">3.3 here</a> and <a href="http://download.eclipse.org/eclipse/downloads/drops/S-3.4M3-200711012000/eclipse-news-M3.html">3.4 here</a>.<br /><br />The main reason I was trying out the new version was to give the C/C++ toolkit <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/CDT/User/NewIn50">CDT 5.0</a> a go.  Doug Schaefer has blogged about it <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2008/05/cdt-50-looks-good-now-looking-ahead.html">here</a>.<br /><br />I was just playing a little with it to see how it compared to the older version and it seems a bit faster.  It has the beginnings of some nice refactorings and templates which should make some common coding tasks a bit simpler.<br /><br />Hopefully when this all comes out <a href="http://wascana.sourceforge.net/">Wascana</a> will have a new version released with a nicely packaged C/C++ development environment for Windows.  It could make a compelling alternative to other IDEs, as well as giving you access to other great tools like PyDev (for Python), Mylyn (task and bug management), and I suppose Java as well...</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Doug Schaefer</div>
<div class='content'>
No worries. I'm working in the CDT 5.0 based-Wascana right now :)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse CDT For Windows - Wascana]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/eclipse-cdt-for-windows-wascana/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-09T21:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/eclipse-cdt-for-windows-wascana</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://wascana.sourceforge.net/">Wascana</a> is the name of the CDT for Windows project run by the excellent <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/">Doug Schaefer</a>.  It provides an installer with Eclipse, the compiler and loads of exras.  The plan is to create a really good Windows desktop IDE.<br /><br />Keep an eye on it over the next few weeks as it should be updating to GCC 4.2.1 and some form of <a href="http://www.wxwidgets.org">wxWidgets</a> support.<br /><br />Certainly if it all comes together there is a powerful argument to use it instead of Visual Studio.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual C++ Orcas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/04/25/visual-c-orcas/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-25T20:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/04/25/visual-c-orcas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Recently public betas for the next version of Visual Studio.NET Orcas (v9.0) were made available.  It is possible to get hold of the free Express versions.<br /><br />You can download Visual C++ Orcas <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/express/future/visualc/default.aspx">here</a>.  And all the other Express versions can be accessed <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/express/future/">here</a>.<br /><br />The C++ compiler with Orcas is a bug fix of the one available with v8.0 (fixing over 180 bugs).  The new rewritten compiler will be available in the version after Orcas.<br /><br />The Visual C++ Team Blog can be read <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vcblog/">here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2005 and TortoiseSVN Subversion Integration - Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/08/visual-studio-2005-and-tortoisesvn/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-08T21:12:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/08/visual-studio-2005-and-tortoisesvn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<span style="font-weight:bold;"><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/07/tortoisesvn-and-visual-studio.html">See the update here.</a></span><br /><br />Hi there everyone,<br /><br />Here is an update to the TortoiseSVN integration into Visual Studio 2005.  This update is a fairly major change since this will only have the changes to external tools, menus and toolbars.  This means when you import these settings you get a new menu at the top of the screen (with icons), a new toolbar with proper TortoiseSVN icons, and context menus for solutions and files.<br /><br />You can download the <a href="http://garry.bodsworth.googlepages.com/SubversionToolbarsAndMenus.zip">new settings file here</a> (it is 9k in size compressed).  All you need to do is go to your Tools menu and choose "Import and Export Settings" and follow the instructions.  Ensure the tick box for which settings to import are all ticked.<br /><br />Here are the original posts from the Subversion integration (and old files are still available).<br /><ul><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/subversion-and-tortoisesvn-programmers.html">Subversion and TortoiseSVN - A programmers best friend</a></li><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/subversion-tortoisesvn-integration.html">Subversion : TortoiseSVN Integration into Visual Studio</a> - A vbs script that will add Subversion to your external tools in Visual Studio 2003 and 2005.</li><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/subversion-tortoisesvn-integration_03.html">Subversion : TortoiseSVN Integration into Visual Studio.NET 2005 Again</a></li><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/tortoisesvn-vsnet-2005-good-stuff.html">TortoiseSVN + VS.NET 2005 = Good Stuff</a> - The original vssettings based integration with additional screenshots that still apply.</li><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/tools-for-tortoisesvn.html">Tools for TortoiseSVN</a> - Some recommended tools for TortoiseSVN.</li><li><a href="http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2006/10/updated-visual-studio-2005-express-and.html">Updated Visual Studio 2005 Express and TortoiseSVN Integration</a> - The first update to the vssettings implementation.</li></ul><br /><a href="http://garry.bodsworth.googlepages.com/SubversionToolbarsAndMenus.zip">DOWNLOAD SETTINGS FILE</a><br /><br /><span style="font-weight:bold;">Edit: </span> Now there is a yet another update - this is now 7k.  This makes a minimum of changes to your IDE as humanly (or inhumanly) possible.  There is still a deficiency in the .vssettings that messes up the build toolbar comboboxes, but this seems unfixable in the current format.<br /><br />Oh, and don't forget to leave some comments as to whether this new stuff is all working for you (along with the new "Add Solution To Repository" functionality.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>bkraul</div>
<div class='content'>
Just a quick question. The article mentions "Context Menus". Are you talking about context menus that show up when right clicking a file or folder in the solution explorer? Because if that is the case, Eventhough I get everything else working fine, I cant see any context menus. Thanks for such a nice solution man!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jon</div>
<div class='content'>
ahh my bad. sorry ;-)</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
This is for TortoiseSVN, not TortoiseCVS.  It is probable that a similar solution can be used for that source control system.<BR/><BR/>Check out TortoiseSVN at http://tortoisesvn.net<BR/><BR/>The latest version of the Visual Studio settings is here:<BR/>http://garrys-brain.blogspot.com/2007/07/tortoisesvn-and-visual-studio.html</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jon</div>
<div class='content'>
I don't know which version of TortoiseCVS you are targeting but none of the executables in your settings file is in my Tortoise installment. I use TortoiseCVS 1.8.31<BR/>Am I suppose to install another version of Tortoise?<BR/> - Jon</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Manish Joisar</div>
<div class='content'>
I have done as per your setting, but i am not getting file wise Update/Commit/Get Lock/Release Lock/Revert. So i can get same way like i am doing it in VSS. It will be great if someone can solve this issue. And i am only interested in VS2005, Subverion, TortoiseSVN & vssettings. Not at all interested in any other tools. I think Garry's Bit can solve this. Please help me.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>sheremetyev</div>
<div class='content'>
If you want to get complete Subversion integration in Visual Studio please have a look at <A HREF="http://www.visualsvn.com/" REL="nofollow">VisualSVN</A>. It wraps TortoiseSVN UI too but provides also seamless support for file operations (renames, moves etc.) and shows status in Solution Explorer. Costs just $49.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
Hi there,<BR/><BR/>Just to answer a couple of previous questions:<BR/><BR/>There is no internal way to resolve a conflict at the moment.<BR/><BR/>It is impossible to add icons to the front of folders since it uses the "External Tools" feature so it can work easily with the Express Editions as well as the Professional ones.<BR/><BR/>If the command being run is wrong (Dotsfuscator) it is possible the order your External Tools is incorrect or when you imported the settings they may not have all been applied.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Frank</div>
<div class='content'>
This looks promising however when I try to execute the "Update" command from the Subversion menu it seems to launch DotFuscater and not do anything else?</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jack</div>
<div class='content'>
Wow, cool stuff. Just 2 comments:<BR/><BR/>1. How to edit conflict and resolve conflict?<BR/>2. Is there anyway to add icon in front of file/folder?<BR/><BR/>Thanks for your great work</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>malks</div>
<div class='content'>
I've just started using the whole SVN/Tortoise/VS2005 stuff... it seems to me that you can't do a checkout from within VS and need to do it from Tortoise directly.  I just used Tortoise to check out to a working dir then opened up in VS and it seemed to work.<br /><br />Coming from an eclipse/CVS background what would be nice is the "decorators" in VS that tell you that you're working with a checked out file.  That is in vs if you change a file, you get a red exclamation mark to remind you that you need to commit your changes.  I might be asking a bit much here though :)<br /><br />Regards,<br />Anthony.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>brian.gullo</div>
<div class='content'>
I keep getting "is not working copy" error.  I'm using vs pro 2005.  How to i get a project checked out?</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>brian.gullo</div>
<div class='content'>
How do i implement the svn checkout functionality.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jordan Elver</div>
<div class='content'>
I'm using professional.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
No problems, glad it works for you now.  Just out of interest are you using Professional or Express?<br /><br />Thanks,<br /><br />Garry</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jordan Elver</div>
<div class='content'>
Weird. When importing the settings file again, I selected the "External Tools List" checkbox and now everything shows up ok. Thanks :)</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Garry Bodsworth</div>
<div class='content'>
They are external tools, so if the executable is not in the place it expects then it is possible that it can't find it.  Is it also disabled on the external tools menu?<br /><br />The settings make the assumption TortoiseSVN is in the default installation location.  If this is the case then do a search and replace on the settings file for:c:\\program files\\TortoiseSVN\\bin\\tortoiseproc.exe<br />And replace it with the location that yours is installed (keeping the double slashes).<br /><br />If that is not the case then try reimporting the settings as VS2005 has this wonderful knack of getting confused when loading settings.<br /><br />Garry</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Jordan Elver</div>
<div class='content'>
Hi,<br />I've imported the settings and everything seems to be ok, but toolbar is greyed out and the menus don't appear. What am I doing wrong?<br /><br />Thanks for working on this :)<br /><br />Cheers, Jordan</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-Source wxWidgets IDE - wxDevC++]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/01/open-source-wxwidgets-ide-wxdev-c/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-01T20:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/11/01/open-source-wxwidgets-ide-wxdev-c</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
In a previous post I have mentioned the splendid free IDE <a href="http://www.codeblocks.org/">Code::Blocks</a>, but in the dark old days of a few years ago, before Microsoft gave stuff away for free and development was quite an expensive endevour, there existed <a href="http://www.bloodshed.net/devcpp.html">DevC++</a>.  It was a free IDE written in Delphi that provided good library management and also was an IDE for GCC in Windows.<br /><br />Over the years other IDEs have sprung up and essentially overtaken Dev-C++ in terms of features and quality.  Then someone decided to make a branch, one that was going to have integrated GUI editing.  This project eventually became <a href="http://wxdsgn.sourceforge.net/">wxDevC++</a>.<br /><br />A new version has just been released with even more features from wxWidgets integrated into the GUI editor.  Most importantly it now has support for Visual C++ compilers (v6, 2003, and 2005) which is interesting.  I need to go and check out this IDE in more detail, but it is good to see it is more than alive and kicking.  If you are a wxWidgets developer it is one of the most comprehensive integrated IDEs for developing and looks like it will be going from strength to strength judging from the <a href="http://wxdsgn.sourceforge.net/changelog.php#610">changelog</a> for this version.<br /><br />And here is a little screenshot with the GUI editor up from their <a href="http://wxdsgn.sourceforge.net/">website</a>:<br /><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger2/5090/4314/1600/thumbnail.png"><img style="cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger2/5090/4314/320/thumbnail.png" border="0" alt="" /></a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Osiris</div>
<div class='content'>
Not to be overly winded, but I think I should recognize your review as being professional quality gary. Excellent work.<BR/><BR/> You have obviously taken some writing courses or have a natural affinity for the art.<BR/><BR/> CAD, RPC, CNC stuff hunh?<BR/> Neat stuff!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Osiris</div>
<div class='content'>
On the topic of: visually oriented programming IDEs with GUI designer matrices, U++ another C++ development tool is up and coming rapidly.<BR/><BR/> It is powerful with stramlined template handling for C++ and the code files look like C#'s in size.<BR/><BR/> The com for the control components never seems to go past a sentence's worth of statement.<BR/><BR/> Succint coding is U++ tagline.<BR/><BR/> The only noticable problems with U++ are: the actual coding comes off as a branching of standard C++ bringing with it a culture shock for C++ programmers, the bug report output is a bit on the vague side, the IDE is a bit too strict with the setup of a project, and there are far too few reference resources.<BR/><BR/> Do not be fooled by the short-comings as the resources that do exist are excellent. With the coding you can be comfortable in about thirty days I would say and your off to the races.<BR/><BR/> The U++ IDE is definitely about brevity, precision, speed, more speed, and cross-platform development with mobile computational devices coming up in the near future.<BR/><BR/> Check into U++; you will not be disappointed.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Osiris</div>
<div class='content'>
Please excuse my typographical errors in my post about wxDevC++.<BR/><BR/> My apologies to all.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Osiris</div>
<div class='content'>
DevC++ was definitely a hallmark in the history of open source IDE technology. Ansi and ISO C/C++ handling as-well-as the Package Manager(PackMan) threw DevC++ to the forefront.<BR/><BR/> wxDevC++ has and will continue to leverage these same powerful frameworks. The look and feel of wxDevC++ is quite similar to Visual Studio products bringing with it a familiarity. Unfortunately the controls are a bit unmanaged and thrown together at the moment.<BR/><BR/> The newer wxWidgets v2.8 recommendations for wxWidget's namespace change is incorporated. Sizer components are however buggy and are of a serious issue within the wxWidget community. Proportions are not handled correctly at all and are paramount within the sizer struct.<BR/><BR/> In conclusion: it would appear that the product is operation with a seriously limited capacity at this point. wxDevC++ does handle generic C++, virtual classes, and references very nicely. This alone says that the product is capable.<BR/><BR/> The development stage of wxDevC++ would realistically put one in the frame of mind that: the IDE is a no holds barred peddle to the metal dev endev. Something this young with this broad a scope would have more serious issues to contend with.<BR/><BR/> the developers of wxDevC++ have been hard at work and have just started on the path. I suspect that the product with such a young and talented staff of developers is going to provide an excellent platform for cross development systems.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
