<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CDT | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/cdt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T16:40:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse CDT For Windows - Wascana]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/eclipse-cdt-for-windows-wascana/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-09T21:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/08/09/eclipse-cdt-for-windows-wascana</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://wascana.sourceforge.net/">Wascana</a> is the name of the CDT for Windows project run by the excellent <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/">Doug Schaefer</a>.  It provides an installer with Eclipse, the compiler and loads of exras.  The plan is to create a really good Windows desktop IDE.<br /><br />Keep an eye on it over the next few weeks as it should be updating to GCC 4.2.1 and some form of <a href="http://www.wxwidgets.org">wxWidgets</a> support.<br /><br />Certainly if it all comes together there is a powerful argument to use it instead of Visual Studio.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IDE - Eclipse CDT]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/12/17/ide-eclipse-cdt/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-17T21:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2006/12/17/ide-eclipse-cdt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</a> is a popular development platform, kind of more than an IDE.  It is based solely around plug-ins and provides a good development environment.  At the moment most of its strength is the Java development and its use for embedded systems (see my previous article about SunSPOTs - that used the Eclipse IDE for remote debugging.<br /><br />One of the projects within it I keep an eye on is the <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/cdt/">CDT</a> project which is a plug-in for C/C++ aiming to be as strong as the Java development.  At the moment it is used a lot for the embedded space, but they want to extend it even further and challenge the <br />Visual Studio IDEs.<br /><br />The guy heading up the CDT project Doug Schaefer has been blogging about the progress of the project for a while.  In the CDT 4.0 roadmap the plan is to use the Windows SDK and have integrated debugging and the suchlike.  His most recent post <a href="http://cdtdoug.blogspot.com/2006/12/migrating-from-visualc-to-cdt.html">"Migrating From Visual C++ to CDT"</a> shows the progress the project is making.  It is always great to have alternatives and Eclipse certainly could help along that route.  Part of the plan is also to add C# support as well from the Windows SDK.  At the moment I would not recommend using CDT in lieu of VS2005 for Windows application development but if your toolchain is make based you may find this a better alternative.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
