<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Games | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T16:47:43+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lucasarts - The Good Old Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/13/lucasarts-good-old-days/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-13T21:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/13/lucasarts-good-old-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Now I am 30 I can get away with saying things were so much better in the olden days.  Actually, no that is not even vaguely true, there is always probably the same good to crap ratio, but the marketing of the crap means you have to dig a little deeper and smarter.<br /><br />Anyway in the olden days Lucasarts the gaming arm of all things Star Wars was actually astoundingly good at making games.  They had the best and brightest and created some of the most unforgettable experiences a person could have on their computer.  Their adventure games were masterclasses for scripting and game echanics.<br /><br />Anyway on to the point of this post - some linkage - two great articles about Lucsart classics, from the very beginning and the very end of their work in adventure games:<br />* <a href="http://www.escapistmagazine.com/articles/view/issues/issue_139/2994-Walk-Don-t-Run">Grim Fandango</a> - Walk Don't Run<br />* <a href="http://www.mixnmojo.com/features/read.php?article=maniacmansion">Maniac Mansion</a> - Lucasarts Secret history<br /><br />And also another completely unrelated gaming article is the excellent retrospective of a game developer starting his commercial career with Donkey Kong on the Atari platform.  Check out the <a href="http://www.dadhacker.com/blog/?p=987">post here</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LWJGL]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/05/lwjgl/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-05T20:26:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/05/lwjgl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Nope, I haven't forgot how to type, but it is a new Java Library for game development.  It provides access to <a href="http://www.openal.org">OpenAL</a> and <a href="http://www.opengl.org">OpenGL</a> through Java.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.lwjgl.org/">LWJGL</a> is designed to allow commercial quality game development in Java and represents many years of development.  It's not a game engine in itself but provides the framework to develop them easily on Java.  It is designed to work on anything with a JVM so it could be used in smartphones and the like.<br /><br />It's interesting from the point of view that this would enable cross-platform development and hopefully give a platform like DirectX.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/03/computer-games/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-03T20:34:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/03/computer-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The past week I have been compiling a list of free (open-source and closed-source) games available for Windows/Mac/Linux.  It is amazing how much there is out there, so I'll probably have to divide it up into multiple posts.<br /><br />There are lots of good quality open-source projects, which makes for lots of source code to eyeball which is really quite cool.<br /><br />But before I start down that road, there is a great blog called <a href="http://indygamer.blogspot.com/">Independent Gaming</a> which has great indy, freeware and open-source games.  The coverage is really comprehensive an has plenty of great reviews.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crystal Space 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/19/crystal-space-10-released/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-19T20:35:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/19/crystal-space-10-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Back in the olden days when I was at university I remember one of the projects I had a play with was <a href="http://www.crystalspace3d.org/main/Main_Page">Crystal Space</a>.  I think I discovered it through the old <a href="http://cg.cs.tu-berlin.de/~ki/engines.html">3D Engines List</a>.<br /><br />Finally after ten years <a href="http://www.crystalspace3d.org/main/Crystal_Space_1.0_and_New_Site">version 1.0 of the Crystal Space library has been released</a>.  It's great to this see this finally happen as it has been so close for so long (in fat it was pretty usable not long into its development).  One of my favourite technologies it has is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal_(computer_graphics)">Portal Rendering</a>, this was added because the original version of <a href="http://www.3drealms.com/">Prey</a> (before it got canned and eventually released recently).  At the time it was going to be revolutionary, but I think that style of rendering can produce some cool and crazy effects.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Programming - Management Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/18/game-programming-management-games/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-18T20:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/01/18/game-programming-management-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my guilty pleasures is <a href="http://www.sigames.com">Football Manager (and previously Championship Manager)</a>, it is definitely my favourite type of game - open-ended, considered, and graphics are not the most important part - it is gameplay.<br /><br />On the <a href="http://www.sigames.com">SI Games website</a> there is a forum with a programmers corner.  There is a great little post on the forum by Marc Vaughan (lead developer type guy) about designing a management game.  It covers in quite a lot of depth, although it is not completely finished.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
