<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SDK | Fragmented Memory]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/categories/sdk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-18T20:47:23+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garry Bodsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/06/iphone-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-06T20:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2008/03/06/iphone-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
After nearly a decade of avoiding having a mobile phone the iPhone was the device that made me change my mind.  It is a great device that means I use my laptop a lot less because I can surf the 'Net and get my imap gmail on it in a very seamless fashion.<br /><br />Today Apple announced the iPhone SDK (the website has completely crashed for me....).  It will give a whole new ease of life to an already excellent product.  One of the greatest aspects of the iPhone is that it is constantly updated with new features like a full computer.<br /><br />There is a comprehensive <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/06/live-from-apples-iphone-press-conference/">write-up on Engadget</a> and <a href="http://arstechnica.com/journals/apple.ars/2008/03/06/developers-licking-their-fingers-over-cocoa-touch-iphone-sdk">Ars Technica</a> of all the announcements today including proper Exchange support.<br /><br />The SDK gives access via Objective-C to the OS features.  You get access to the accelerometers and multi-touch when writing your apps.  XCode provides the environment to develop in and there is an iPhone simulator. The features you have access to are:<br />* Keychain<br />* Bonjour<br />* SQLite<br />* Core Location<br />* Quicktime media layer<br />* Core Audio<br />* Core Image<br />* Core Animation<br />* PDF rendering<br />* OpenAL<br />* OpenGL ES<br /><br />The games look pretty damn good on the iPhone fromt he presentation from Super Monkey Ball to Spore to the specially designed Touch Fighter.  It looks like a Wii style changing of the game by using the advantages that the device offers rather than dwelling on what is now missing in comparison to gaming systems.<br /><br />Also the apps created will be distributed by the App Store that will be run by Apple.  If you develop free or open-source apps Apple will host them and distribute them for free.<br /><br />Also there is a leak of the BBC iPlayer for the iPhone mentioned in <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/06/live-from-apples-iphone-press-conference/comments/10866456/">this comment</a> on Engadget.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Adi</div>
<div class='content'>
<a rel="external" href="http://orientinspiration.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oes  Tsetnoc</a> one of the ways in which we can learn seo besides <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com/archives/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a>.  By participating in the <a rel="external" href="http://mncmakina.com/2009/09/oes-tsetnoc-seo-contest/" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> or <a rel="external" href="http://ulaznice.info/mengembalikan-jati-diri-bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> we can improve our seo skills. To find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/738688-Oes-Tsetnoc.html" rel="nofollow">Oest Tsetnoc</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://kusukaseo.info/981750-Oes-Tsetnoc-Support.html" rel="nofollow">Oes Tsetnoc</a> pages. And to find more information about <a rel="external" href="http://duniasoer.com" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> please visit my <a rel="external" href="http://catatanblogger.info/464655-Mengembalikan-Jati-Diri-Bangsa.html" rel="nofollow">Mengembalikan Jati Diri Bangsa</a> pages. Thank you So much.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL News and SDK Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/27/opengl-news-and-sdk-released/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-27T21:03:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.fragmentedmemory.com/blog/2007/02/27/opengl-news-and-sdk-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Volume 3 of the <a href="http://www.opengl.org">OpenGL</a> has been released, <a href="http://www.opengl.org/pipeline/vol003/">read it here</a>.<br /><br />In this volume there is a lot of good stuff.  There is more about the OpenGL process, information about OpenGL ES (the embedded platform), a look at the OpenGL SDK, and plenty more.<br /><br />The OpenGL SDK has been <a href="http://www.opengl.org/sdk/">released here</a>.  It is not an SDK in a traditional sense but a collection of third-party constributions.  It contains documentation, libraries, tutorials, and tools.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
